at Calvary and he trotted how alone is
that good news or bad news that's good
news the reason why he trotted alone is
because he didn't want any of us to trot
it so he basically said hey I took the
wrath of God by myself
so that you would not have to sale not
for sale
Heavenly Father please speak through me
and speak to your people lord help me to
take what you have given me and to break
bread to share with your people draw us
close to you as a result is our prayer
in Jesus name Amen
1st Kings chapter 21 beginning with
verse 1 the Bible says and it came to
pass after these things that neighbour
the jezreelite had a vineyard which was
in Jezreel hard by the palace of Ahab
king of samaria and that phrase hard by
the palace of ahab simply means very
close near to the palace of ahab and a
hab was a wicked king of Israel the
Bible goes into this story of this man
named neighbor who has this this
vineyard that it was close to the Palace
of Ahab the king of Samaria verse 2 and
Ahab said unto neighbor saying or a they
have spake on to name of saying give me
thy vineyard
that I may have it for a garden of herbs
because because it is near unto my house
and I will give thee for it a better
vineyard
or if it seemed good to be I will give V
the worth of it in money that that
sounds like a good deal
give me your vineyard and I will give
you a better vineyard or I will pay for
it in caps the Bible says in verse 3 and
neighbors said to Ahab the Lord forbid
it me that I should give thee what the
inheritance of my father's unto thee and
a had came into his house heavy and
displeased because of the word which
neighbors the jezreelite had spoken unto
him for he said I will not give the
inheritance of my father's in other
words it is not for sale
and he laid him down upon his bed and
turned his face away and would eat no
bread verse 5 but just but Jezebel his
wife now you know that name Jezebel is
just not a good name neither is a good
character but Jezebel his wife came to
him and said unto him why is thy spirit
so sad that thou eatest no bread and he
said unto her because I spake unto
neighbour the jezreelite and said unto
him give me thy vineyard for money or
else if it please the I will give thee
another vineyard for it and he answered
I will not give thee my vineyard and
Jezebel his wife said unto him does thou
now govern the kingdom of Israel arise
and eat bread and let thine heart be
merry I will give thee the vineyard of
naboth the jezreelite how she plans to
do that we will soon see but I want you
to get the story
they have Caesars vineyard it is owned
by neighbor and he says to him give
this vineyard ah I'll pay for it I'll
buy it from you or I'll give you another
vineyard better than it I'll give you
another vineyard better I'll give you
another one
better are you with me and neighbors
says no I will not it's my father's
inheritance and God forbid that I give
it to you and when they have hears this
he's upset he's angry he goes home and
and and he he's basically pouting and
his wife looks at him and says what's
the matter and he tells her what happens
and then she says don't worry about it
you're the king I will get that vineyard
for you let's break this down
why did neighbor refuse to sell his
vineyard I want you to turn with me hold
your place here we're going to go to the
Book of Leviticus chapter 25 Leviticus
the twenty-fifth chapter and in
Leviticus 25 if you read from verses 1
through 3 or 1 through 22 God there is
is basically telling the children of
Israel how he would bless their land and
that it would be a fruitful land this
land that was to be flowing with milk
and honey
and and then in verse 23 this is what it
says the land shall not be sold for ever
for the land is whose mine for your
strangers and sojourners with me God
tells them you're not to sell this land
number 1 because it's mine and number 2
because it's gonna be a land that is
flowing with milk and honey it's gonna
be a fruitful land therefore I do not
want you to sell this land it is never
to be sold so neighbors was simply
obeying the command of of God in numbers
36 verse 7 I'll read it in your hearing
it goes on to say this regarding the
land it says so shall not the
inheritance of the children of Israel
remove
tribe to tribe for every one of the
children of Israel shall keep himself to
the inheritance of the tribe of his
father's verse 9 neither shall the
inheritance removed from one tribe to
another but every one of the tribes of
the children of Israel shall keep
himself to his own inheritance in other
words there were not to sell the land
because it was part of their inheritance
in Genesis chapter 15 and verse 7 you
will remember that God called Abraham
out of the land of ur and the Bible
actually says he said unto him I am the
Lord that brought thee out of ur of the
Chaldeans to give thee this land to
inherit it so the land that God gave to
Israel was their inheritance and God was
basically saying do not sell your
inheritance do not what everyone sell
your inheritance your inheritance is not
for sale in Leviticus 26 verse 3 and
verse 4 again I'll read it in your
hearing it says if you walk in my
statutes and keep my Commandments and do
them then will I give you reign in due
season and the land shall yield her
increase and the trees of the field
shall yield their fruits the yielding of
fruits in these vineyards in this land
was a sign of obedience to God and
therefore God said never sell the land
because the land is sort of like a an
agreement that you and I have you obey
me and I'm gonna make your land fruitful
you see beloved what I want to tell you
this morning is that God has given every
one of us an inheritance and your
inheritance
say it with me is not for sale never
sell it no matter how good the deal
looks never sell your inheritance
because God says that this inheritance
means I'm going to make you fruitful in
Galatians chapter 5 it tells us that the
fruit of the Spirit is what's love joy
peace long-suffering gentleness goodness
faith meekness temperance God has Saints
you listen I am giving you these things
as an inheritance when you accept me
you
you for an inheritance no matter how
much the world comes to you and offers
you something different let me ask you a
question
has the world ever come to you and
offered you something better
hey hey you have what hey listen I will
give you something better in exchange
for what you're holding on to now do you
think Satan wants your inheritance and
do you think that he will do whatever he
can to get that inheritance but I would
listen to me do not sell your
inheritance don't sell yourself out of
your inheritance no matter what the
devil comes to you with you tell him not
for sale you remember the story of Esau
do you remember how Esau came in from a
hunting one day and the Bible says that
Esau was faint faint the word means
weary and he was so faint that that he
was like I need something to eat now I
need to eat it right now and Jacob his
brother it's like okay if you want
something to eat
what did he ask sell me your birthright
and these so I was like what good is his
birthright gonna do me if I'm dead here
take the birthright he had no regard for
his birthright and he sold it for a pot
of food how many of us are like Esau
selling our birthright for a pot of food
and listen Esau would not prop would
probably not have done that had he not
been wary had he not been faint so you
know what the enemy tries to do he tries
to get you weary he tries to wear you
out to the point where you don't regard
your inheritance anymore
that's what he's after
he's trying to wear you out so that you
will give up your inheritance but
Matthew 8 verse 36 tells us this for
what shall it profit a man if he gain
the whole world and lose his own soul or
what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul beloved your birthright
should never be on the table for sale
your inheritance what God has given you
Galatians 6 verse 7 says this be not
deceived God is not mocked for
whatsoever a man soweth that shall he
also reap
remember this was neighbor this vineyard
a place where he would sow his own fruit
and and and and and reap that food the
Bible says here do not be mopped
whatsoever man saw that shall he read
for he that soweth to his flesh shall of
the flesh reap corruption but he that
soweth to the spirit shall of the Spirit
reap everlasting life and then listen to
these next words and let us not be weary
in well-doing for in due season we shall
reap if we saw and faint
you know we can be dramatic sometimes
huh I pass it out
and sometimes we use that that faintness
as an excuse to sell what God has given
us
I was faint that's why I did it I was
weary that's why I did it but the Bible
says do not be mocked you reap what you
sow therefore do not be weary now that's
a question honestly how many of us have
ever struggled with being weary it's a
struggle we all face but God says listen
don't faint in fact in fact Isaiah 40
verse 31 says this but they that wait
upon the Lord shall renew their strength
they shall mount up with wings as Eagles
they shall run and not be weary they
shall walk and not things God says wait
upon me wait upon me trust me don't grow
weary
don't go faint and don't sell your
inheritance so understand that a Satan
can't make you weary in order to get you
away from your inheritance then he will
straight out persecute you come come
back with me the first kings and I want
you to notice verse 5 first kings
remember we leave off where Jezebel is
like oh what he said what okay don't
worry about it I got this and I want you
to notice what happens first kings
chapter 5 I'm sorry first Kings chapter
21 first kings 21 and let's pick up with
verse 7 and Jezebel his wife said unto
him dust I'll now govern the Kingdom of
Israel arise and eat bread and let thine
heart be merry I will give thee the
vineyard of naboth the jezreelite so she
wrote listen carefully so she wrote
letters in a Habs name and
seal them with his seal and sent the
letters unto the elders and to the
nobles that were in his city dwelling
with neighbors and she wrote in a letter
saying proclaim a fast and set neighbor
on high among the people in other words
exalt neighbors before the people check
this out guys
burst him and set how many two men sons
of Belial that means sons of wickedness
before him to bear witness against him
saying thou didst blaspheme God and the
King and then carry him out and stone
him that he may die they set neighbors
up framed him and then took him outside
the city and stoned him verse 11 and the
men of the city even the elders and the
nobles who were the inhabitants of his
city did as Jezebel had sent unto them
and as it was written in the letters
which she had sent unto them they
proclaimed the fast set neighbors on
high among the people and there came in
two men children of Belial and sat
before him and the men of Belial
witnessed against him even against
neighbors in the presence of the people
saying neighbors did blaspheme God and
the king then they carried him forth out
of the city out of the where everyone
and stone him with stones that he died
then they sent to Jezebel saying
nebith is stoned and is what and is dead
and it came to pass when Jezebel heard
this that neighbored was stoned and was
dead that Jezebel said to Ahab arise
take possession of the vineyard of
neighbor the jezreelite which he refused
to give thee for money for native is not
alive but dead but I would listen to me
if Satan cannot get you to sell your
birthright
he will straight-out persecute you for
it the Bible tells us 2nd Timothy
chapter 3 verse 12 ye all they that live
godly in Christ Jesus shall suffer what
persecution is this what they did to
neighbors they took him out of his own
vineyard out of his own garden and
stoned him 1st Peter chapter 4 verse 12
says this beloved think it not strange
concerning the fiery trial which is to
try you as though some strange thing
happened to you but rejoice in as much
as you are partakers of Christ's
sufferings that when his glory shall be
revealed you may be glad also with
exceeding joy but not it is Satan cannot
wear you out and cause you to faint he
will wear you out through persecution
Daniel 7:25 says that he wears out the
Saints of the Most High that means he
persecutes listen beloved don't think
it's strange when you are being
persecuted for righteousness sake don't
think it's strange that when you refuse
to yield to the to the advances of the
enemy that he will not come at you and
try to make life so miserable for you
that you totally give up
the sad fact though is that many of us
are really not like namath at all we are
kind of more like
Adam you remember him what did Adam do
with his inheritance he sold it he sold
it it was not his to sell by the way was
it whose wasn't it was gone
Genesis 1:26 the Bible says God said let
us make man in our image after our
likeness and let them have dominion over
the fish of the earth and over the fowl
of the air and over the cattle and over
all the earth so God made man and gave
him dominion over the earth
it was his inheritance and he should
have kept it it was not for sale the
Bible actually says in Genesis 2 verse 8
and the Lord God planted a garden
eastward in Eden and he put the man whom
he had formed there so God gave Adam and
Eve a garden a vineyard what did he give
them everyone a vineyard a garden and
what did Adam and Eve end up doing they
ended up selling what was not theirs to
sell in the first place they sold their
inheritance but praise God that God did
not leave the situation like that
because the Bible says in Genesis 3:21
that God would send a seed God would
send someone that would come to redeem
this earth and that someone was Jesus
Christ and beloved I want you to get the
picture because when Jesus comes on the
scene beloved he has listen Exodus 19
verse 5 the Bible says now therefore if
you will obey my voice indeed and keep
my covenant then you shall be a peculiar
treasure above me to me above all the
people of the earth for all the earth is
mine who does earth belong to it belongs
to God
it is Jesus he is the one that created
this earth so when he comes to earth
when he is born as a man
what he has done is he has inherited the
earth it's very interesting because the
word nameth the name namath it actually
means fruits and and I want you to
understand that the Bible tells us it
actually calls Jesus Christ the first
fruits so when Jesus came to this earth
he was coming to to demonstrate that
this world is not Satan's it is his this
is mine by inheritance it is interesting
to also note that that that when Jesus
comes upon the scene you remember that
knate knate our neighbors was a
jezreelite he lived in the city of
Jezreel and that city Jezreel it is
actually it actually means God will so I
need you to catch that God will so what
does namath mean you're making me faint
namath means what fruit Jezreel means
God will so when Jesus comes to this
earth he comes as the first fruits when
the Bible spoke of Abraham he said when
God said to Abraham Abraham I'm going to
give you a land you're gonna inherit
that man you and your seed the Bible
tells us that the seed that was being
spoken of was Jesus himself so this was
his inheritance God saying I'm going to
sow in this field this earth and the
sowing that I'm going to do is going to
bring forth a
bountiful harvest of fruits don't sell
the land why because this land is going
to produce much fruits let me ask you a
question what is the process of
producing fruits how do you get fruits
what do you have to do you plant the
seed something has to be put in the
ground and that thing that is put into
the ground
comes back out of the ground in a
different form
y'all are feeling me and so God said
listen I am pert I am this earth is mine
because this earth is going to provide a
bountiful harvest there's going to be a
lot of fruits coming up out of the
ground one day so so remember in the
story a hab wants the garden for himself
so he approaches neighbor and says hey
what will you give me for your garden
come with me Matthew Matthew chapter 4
because you see a have wanted to make
neighbors garden a part of his own
kingdom you are not feeling me did you
hear what I just said a hab wanted to
make neighbors garden a part of his own
kingdom so he goes to him
and is basically tempting him to go
against the plain word of God Matthew
chapter 4 Matthew chapter 4 verse 1
please notice what the Bible says here
Matthew chapter 4 verse 1 the Bible says
then was Jesus led up in the spirit into
the wilderness to be tempted of the
devil and when he had fasted forty days
and forty nights he was afterward a
hunger and the tempter came to him say
and say ah saying
sell me your inheritance I know why you
are here you're here to try to win this
earth so listen let's make a deal and
these three temptations if you be the
Son of God turn this stone to bread he
then takes me to a high place and says
throw yourself down and and if you're
gone or if you're the son of God your
father will save you and then he finally
says look all this will I give you hold
on hold on look come down with me verse
verse seven or verse verse eight again
the devil taketh him up into the an
exceeding high mountain and showed him
how much oh listen I know why you're
here if I exchange for you all the
kingdoms of the world will you give me
the field will you sell me your
inheritance and Jesus basically if we
were to sum it up Jesus basically
replied not for sale why why am I not
willing to sell because of the fruit
that's going to come forth from this
land
Jesus was unwilling to sell because of
you
now how does that make you feel does
that make you feel special not for sale
I'm not giving up this land but what's
so pretty look at the land is crazy it's
you know it's it's full of sin and Jesus
says no this land there's going to be a
bountiful harvest coming from this land
and I will not sell it you can't have
them
Psalm 94 verse 14 the Bible says for the
Lord will not cast off his people
neither will he forsake his inheritance
Romans 8:35 should have a special
meaning to you now it says who shall
separate us from the love of Christ
shall tribulation or distress or
persecution or famine or nakedness or
peril or sword in other words Jesus was
willing to go through all this to keep
the land because of you my people are
precious to me and I will not sell this
land for anything that's how precious
this land is to Jesus that's how
precious you are to Jesus Oh get the
story now a hab I mean Satan is like you
won't sell it the Bible says the devil
goes away leaving leaving Jesus after
these contagious devil realizes I'm not
going to get it from him through bribery
I'm not going to get it from him through
through him being faint or weary because
by the way was Jesus weary in the
wilderness for forty days and forty
nights and even in his weariness he was
like not for sale not selling it alright
so if I can't buy it from you then we
need to set you up so so what
is what happens come with me to Matthew
chapter 26 you need to see this Matthew
chapter 26 note what happens Matthew 26
verse 3 Matthew 26 verse 3 the Bible
says these words then assemble together
the chief priests and the scribes and
the elders of the people unto the palace
of the high priest who's who was called
Caiaphas and consulted that they might
take Jesus subtly and what let me ask
you a question what did Jezebel what was
Jezebel's plan to get the land kill
neighbors do you see here a parallel do
you see here Satan going ok I can't I
can't get him to sell it to me so what
I'm gonna do is I'm going to kill him
and if you check out the rest of the
story it's really quite interesting
because if you jump down with me a few
verses actually down to verse 46 verse
46 just notice what the Bible says here
Matthew 26 and verse 46 are you there
[Music]
now I'm sorry verse 46
the Bible says rise let us be going
behold he is at hand that does betray me
and while he yet spake lo Judas one of
the twelve came with him and with him a
great multitude with swords and staves
from the chief priests and elders of the
people and now he would now he that
betrayed him gave him a sign saying
whomever I shall kiss the same as he
hold him fast and if you continue
reading on the Bible tells us verse
60 I believe it is verse 57 and they
that had laid hold on Jesus led him away
to Caiaphas the high priest where the
scribes and the elders were assembled
but Peter followed him afar off onto the
high priests office and went in and sat
with the servants to see the end now the
chief priests and elders and all the
counsels sought false wot's witnesses
against Jesus to put him to death but
found none yay though many false
witnesses came yet they found none and
at the last came how many do you
remember that number two false witnesses
come against Namath the neighbor to say
yeah you are guilty of blasphemy let me
answer the question what did they accuse
Jesus of being guilty of claiming to be
God and blasphemy and so what did they
do
where did they crucify him do you catch
this they crucified him out side the
city did they set him on high Jesus said
a knife I he once lifted up will do
what's draw all men unto me now listen
to me you got to understand this you see
when a how did this he thought that he
had secured his kingdom he had secured
his vineyard I should say but little
does a have realized that in this very
act in killing they both watch this come
back with me to first Kings chapter 21
you need to see this first Kings 21
verse 16 first Kings chapter 21 notice
what happens here first Kings 21 verse
16 and it came to pass when Ahab heard
that name of was dead that
rose up to go down to the vineyard of
naboth the jezreelite to take possession
of its can you imagine a hat like all
happy like yeah this is mine now
everything is good to go he is out of
the way and this is all me but you got
to understand something because this was
the very thing that led to a halves
death listen to me look at verse the
Bible says in verse verse 60 over 17 and
the word of the Lord came to Elijah
Elijah the Tishbite saying arise go down
to me 1/2 king of Israel which is in
Scenario behold he is in the vineyard of
neighbors whether he has gone down to
what to possess it and thou shalt speak
unto him saying thus saith the Lord
has thou killed and also taken
possession and thou shalt speak unto him
saying thus saith the Lord in the place
where dogs licked the blood of neighbors
shall dogs lick thy blood even thine
do you catch what's happening here the
very act of a putting to death
nebith secured his own destruction okay
y'all now feelin me
the very act in neighbor thinking this
is how I'm gonna get victory I'm gonna
put I'm sorry and a-hat thinking this
I'm gonna get victory I'm gonna put him
to death so that I can get his filled in
that very act his own death and defeat
were secured beloved listen to me in the
very act of Satan seeking to destroy the
life of Christ in the very act of Satan
trying to brew
who's the heel of Jesus in that very act
he secured his own destruction
damira how jesus said except a kernel of
wheat a die and is buried it abides
alone but if it die and is buried then
it will want bring forth much fruit
listen guys do you realize you need to
see come come back with me come back
with me to Luke chapter 13 verse 19 Luke
chapter 13 verse 19 let's see if we can
get it up on the screen and then we're
going to go to John 18 verse 1 Luke
chapter 13 verse 19 it is like a grain
of a mustard seed which a man took and
cast into his wand talking about the
kingdom of heaven Jesus is giving this
analogy and he says it is like a mustard
seed which a man took and cast into his
garden and it grew and waxed a great
tree and all the fowls of the air
enlarged their branch in it beloved
Jesus Christ is that seed that was
planted in the garden of the Lord the
very planting of that seed secured the
destruction of Satan in fact debris when
Jesus was in the Garden of Gethsemane I
just gave it away man the Garden of
Gethsemane It was as if while he was in
that garden God was reminding him listen
he was struggling with this sacrifice
and God was saying it was like he was
being reminded you have come here to
redeem the garden you have come here
because there is going to be a bountiful
harvest
don't turn back now he saw your face in
the Garden of Gethsemane and said no I
will not sell it I will not walk away
from this and in fact when Jesus died
John 19 verse 41 when Jesus died
remember where do they take Jesus from
where do they find him in the garden
they tried to take Jesus from the garden
and the Bible tells us that when Jesus
died John 19 verse 41 now in the place
where he was crucified there was a and
in the garden a new what we're never man
had so where was Jesus buried where was
Jesus planted and the fact that he was
planted in a garden signified that he
would be the first fruit to come forth
from the ground to pave the way for
other fruits to come from the ground now
check this out guys the Bible tells us
that in the same place that Nate that
neighbors died would be the same place
that a hab would I did you catch that
just not God said to Elijah tell they
have that in the same place and this is
powerful you gotta see this in the same
place so the question is where did Jesus
die you all know the answer right he
died where he died at Calvary but where
was Calvary outside you guys
Jesus died outside the city does the
Bible tell us that in the same place
that Jesus died there's a Bible tell us
that Satan will die in that same place
it does doesn't it now know what you're
saying wait a minute where in the world
does the Bible say that Satan will die
where Jesus died listen guys come how do
I do this out of there look Isaiah let
me read in your hearing okay follow me
closely Isaiah 63 verse 3 speaking
prophetically of Jesus it says I have
trodden the winepress alone and not the
people there was none with me where did
Jesus shroud the winepress of God's
wrath at Calvary and he trotted how
alone is that good news or bad news
that's good news the reason why he
trotted alone is because he didn't want
any of us to trot it so he basically
said hey I took the wrath of God by
myself so that you would not have to I
died on Calvary so that you would not
have to Galatians three to 313 says
Christ has redeemed us from the curse of
the law being made a curse for us for it
is written cursed is everyone that hangs
on a tree Christ became the curse for us
and he became the curse for us outside
the city Psalm 75 verse 8 for in the
hand of the Lord there is a cup and the
wine is red it is full of mixture and he
pours out the same but the dregs thereof
all the wicked of the earth shall wring
them out and drink them Christ drank
that cup for us in the Garden of
Gethsemane and on the cross and he did
it all himself so that you and I would
not have to experience that he took it
upon himself
remember he prayed if it be possible let
this walk
let this cup pass from me the Bible says
that he took our sins upon himself and
now listen carefully but beloved because
this is this is the main point I want to
get across to you now so please follow
carefully Hebrews 2 12 verse 2 says this
looking unto Jesus the author and
finisher of our faith who for the joy
that was set before him endured the
cross despising the shame and has sat
down at the right hand of the throne of
God what does it mean despising the
shame what do you think despising the
shame meant did the Jesus experience
shame on our behalf
where did he experience that shame at
the cross the cross is the place of
shame what I say it's the place of shame
it's the place of reproach outside the
city Christ took our shame upon himself
now watch this
Hebrews 13 11 tells us this for the
bodies of those beasts whose blood is
brought into the sanctuary by the high
priest for sin are burned without the
camp wherefore jesus also that he might
be that he might sanctify the people
with his own blood suffered without the
gate and then it says this let us go
forth therefore unto him without the
camp bearing his reproach God is
inviting us now go outside the city when
now to bear what's his reproach listen
to because he's inviting you to do it
when now what is inviting you to do it
now because you don't want to be there
later
did you catch what I just said if you
don't just follow along God is inviting
us now
hey symbolically go outside the city now
go to that place where is shame now go
there now experience it now let us bear
the reproach of being a Christian now
you see below the world is trying to rob
you of your inheritance through shame
you're a what you really believe in that
Bible do you see what I'm talking about
the world's weapon to try to get you to
sell your inheritance is shame so Jesus
says listen don't be ashamed to me they
are the same bear their approach do it
now be willing to be ashamed for my
calls like Paul said I am not ashamed
they're the same but don't be ashamed
bear the same be willing to stand up and
say yeah that's who I am this is what I
believe bear the same but don't be
ashamed and there's a very simple reason
why beloved listen do you remember the
book of Hebrews 11 chapter 2 verse 24
rather it says by faith Moses when he
was come to years refused to be called
Pharaoh's son or Pharaohs be called the
son of Pharaoh's daughter choosing
rather to suffer affliction with the
people of God than to enjoy the
pleasures of sin for seasoned esteeming
the reproach of Christ greater riches
than the treasures of Egypt what did
Moses do he preferred the reproach of
Christ than the riches of Ahab the
riches of Egypt the riches of this world
at the end of time we're told in Joel
chapter 3 in fact come there with me
Joel chapter 3 let's get it up on the
screen Joel chapter 3 verse 12 and 13
Joel chapter 3 verse 12 and 13 the Bible
says let the heathen be wakened and come
up to the valley of jehoshaphat for
there will I sit to judge all the
heathen roundabout verse 13 put you in
the sickle for the harvest of what every
one the harvest is ripe come get you
down for the presses for the fats
overflow for the wickedness is great God
says at the end of time there's going to
be a great slaughter in the valley of
Jehosaphat anyone know where the valley
of Jehoshaphat is what what event is is
talking about anyone know this is
talking about
final judgment the valley of jehoshaphat
the the there's going to be a great
slaughter and check this out
the Bible tell us in Zechariah 13 that
when Jesus comes again his feet are
going to stand upon the mount of wats
olives and what is going to be
descending down from heaven as Jesus
comes down to the earth it's going to be
the place called the New Jerusalem and
beloved listen to me at that time the
people who are out side the city are the
ones who were ashamed of Jesus Christ
the ones who refused to go out to where
Jesus was bearing the shame bearing the
cross the ones who referred the ones who
were easily let the ones who sold their
birthright the ones who said I don't
want a part of this land I don't want a
part of this inheritance at the end of
time guess where they end up the same
place that Jesus died for them that's
the crazy thing jesus said I'm gonna die
outside the city for you so that you
don't have to die outside the city and
yet because they refused the reproach of
Jesus here the wicked stand outside the
city what a waste of the sacrifice of
Jesus we're closed not names you to
listen to these verses mark 8 verse 36
Jesus said for what shall it profit a
man if he gain the whole world and yet
lose his own soul or what shall a man
give in exchange for his own soul and
the very next verse says whosoever
therefore shall be ashamed of me and of
my words in this adulterous and sinful
generation of him also shall the son of
be ashamed when he cometh in the glory
of his father with the Holy Angels as
Susan comes out I want to let you know
something outside the city there are
three places of significance outside the
city of Jerusalem in the days of Jesus
there were three places of significance
one was Calvary it was outside the city
two was Gethsemane it was outside the
city and both of those places were what
gardens number three the other
significant place outside the city was a
place called Gehenna you know what that
is it's the place where bodies were
burned and beloved I want you to
understand that when Jesus and that New
Jerusalem touches this earth at the very
end of this world's history the people
outside the city will remember something
very specific they will remember the one
who died outside the city for them they
will remember the cup he drank on their
behalf and they will lament the fact
that as they are being destroyed they
will lament the fact that they rejected
what happened outside the city for them
and beloved my appeal to you today is
this it's time for us to go out of the
city now it's time for us to bear the
reproach and the shame of Christ now we
love Him because He first loved us
he died for a world that rejected him
that put him out of the city that's who
he died for him he didn't die for the
righteous because if he died for the
righteous not one of us would be saved
he died for the wicked he died to redeem
those who were his enemies and he's
pleading now accept my sacrifice on your
behalf and what of my simple appeal is
live if you if you're saying to yourself
today Lord make me willing to bear the
shame and the reproach help me to not be
so quick to sell my inheritance that's
true desire I want you to raise your
hand as Susan comes up she's going to
lead us in prayer Lord let me have that
mentality that my inheritance is not for
sale
if you can please kneel Susan prays